

"Success is the sum of small efforts repeated day in and day out."
- Robert Collier

## **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

My passion began many years ago with web design and evolved into a curiosity for how to "build stuff". I love being immersed in the programming world and am seeking a Junior Developer opportunity. I am dedicated to learning my craft and would love to contribute to a team while building upon my current skill set.

Skills include:

Full-Stack Web Development, Object-Oriented Programming / Test Driven Development / Digital Project Management / Online Marketing Collateral / Graphic Design

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Ruby, HTML, CSS3, Javascript

**Frameworks & Tools:** Ruby on Rails, jQuery, PostgresSQL, Heroku, AWS, Twitter Bootstrap, Git / Github, WordPress, Middleman, Photoshop

### **EDUCATION**

**Syracuse University**, Syracuse, NY, 2003-2007 Martin J. Whitman School of Management Bachelor of Science; Entrepreneurship & Emerging Enterprises Dean's List

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Development, Algorithm, and Data Structures Foundations - Firehose Project, June - Oct 2015

An intensive 15-week program in which I studied to become a web developer / programmer. I learned how to develop web applications, break down complex problems into more manageable pieces and many tools of the trade.

- Learned how to build-out CRUD Rails apps following standard Rails conventions (without scaffolding), involving mailers, validations, image uploading on AWS S3 and nested RESTful routes.
- Implemented tests using MiniTest's Test::Unit Syntax for both unit and functional tests.
- Learned front-end development fundamentals and implemented responsive design in web applications.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Biz Dev Now, Remote, March 2014 - January 2016

### Digital Project Manager / Web Developer

Developed websites for small and medium-sized businesses. WordPress theme customization and maintenance. UI design with Balsamiq wireframing tool. Graphic asset creation with Photoshop. Sourced and hired freelance web developers and graphic designers.

SmartsiteMovement, Aug 2012 - Sep 2014

#### Founder

Created standalone mobile websites for small businesses.

Progressive Business Publications, Malvern, PA, Feb 2011 - Sep 2012

### **Market Analyst**

Managed email marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 to mid-sized companies. Revised marketing copy for struggling email marketing campaigns to improve lead generation results. Designed landing pages and made content updates to WordPress newsletter site.

FedSources, Washington, DC Metro, 2010 - 2011

## **Market Intelligence Analyst**

Tracked and analyzed federal government contract opportunities released by U.S. Navy agencies. Conducted in-depth internet and primary research for clients. Built professional relationships with Navy Contracting Officers. Attended industry conferences and published reports for company website.

Help Unlimited Temps & Office Team, Washington, DC Metro, 2008 - 2009

## **Administrative Assistant**

Temp Assignments:

DC Housing Finance Agency

Provided assistance to public regarding real estate buyer program and admin support to agency.

Giuliani Associates Architects Inc.

Data entry, AP/AR, payroll assistance, project folder maintenance

ComputerTraining.com, Newark, DE, 2007 - 2008

# **Assistant Director of Admissions**

Conducted education sales for Microsoft Certification Program. Managed large database of potential student leads and schedule campus visits for Director of Admissions. Provided solid follow-up with potential students. Met and exceeded student enrollment goals.